DANIEL CABALLERO

Data Engineer with a PhD in Computational Mechanics and a passion for Information Technology. I am passionate about learning and applying new technologies to find better solutions for different types of problems. I believe that AI and Big Data represent the future of many disciplines, and I look forward to be a part of that future. I have experience as a CAE Engineer, Project Manager, Programmer, and Data Analyst.



CONTACT

Full Name: Daniel Enrique Caballero

Age: 32

From: Argentina

Personnummer: 880804-5838

✓ danielcaballero88@gmail.com

+46 764 367 221

Stockholm, Sweden

@danielcaballero88

n Daniel Caballero

SKILLS

Languages

Portuguese

English

Italian

Swedish

Spanish (native)

Programming Python Rash **SQL** C++ **Fortran** ΜΔΤΙ ΔΒ HTML/CSS **JavaScript** LaTeX **Operating Systems** Linux Windows **MacOS Software & Tools** Visualization (e.g. matplotlib, seaborn, ...) Data handling/analysis (e.g. numpy, scipy, pandas, ...) Git Office **Modeling & Simulation** (e.g. Ansys Fluent, SolidWorks, ...)

WORK HISTORY

10/2020

♥ Wondersign, California, USA

Data Analyst

Clean and normalize big datasets to make them available in production. Write Python scripts and notebooks for scraping/mining, merging, parsing, re-formating and clustering data. Create data pipelines with a mix of technologies: Blendr, ProductsUp, Google Cloud Platform, and more.

1 04/2016 - 08/2020

GIAC, Mar del Plata, Argentina
 CAE Engineer

Build models and perform simulations in the fields of Computational Fluid Dynamics & Solid Mechanics. Main tools: Ansys Fluent and Simulia Abaqus for simulations; Paraview, MATLAB and Python for Data Analysis & Visualization of results.

2014 - 2016

♀ La Paloma Brewing

Sales & Logistics Manager

Mar del Plata. Argentina

Multi-role in a growing brewing company. Manage stock and coordinate shipments. Treat with customers and distributors. Assist in project management and production scheduling.

2012 - 2014

P Ternium, Buenos Aires, Argentina
Supervise engineering projects. Design plan of action, write technical specifications, draw blue-prints, assign schedule. Coordinate execution, solve emerging problems in-site.

EDUCATION

2007 - 2012

National University of Mar del Plata

Mechanical Engineering

Graduated with the best average grade of my class (8.62 / 10), gaining a Distinctive GPA Mention.

2016 - 2020

PhD in Computational Mechanics
Specialized in Finite Element Analysis (FEA) and Computational Fluid Dynamics (CFD).

PhD in Computational Fluid Dynamics (CFD).

GENERAL SKILLS

Logical Thinking	Problem Solving	Management	Communication
Multi-Tasking	Research	Documentation	Data Mining
Data Modeling	Data Analysis	Data Visualization	Programming
Scripting Machine Learning Simulation Bash Python Numpy			
Scipy Scrapy Selenium Django Flask SQLAlchemy SQL			
Google Cloud Platform			

MY TIME

